Stephen Popovich Web Developer/Software Enigneer





408-613-4849

stephenpopovich16@gmail.com

Portfolio:

www.stephenmpopovich.com

SUMMARY

An engineer with exceptional front-end development skills and a passion for user experience. I'm highly motivated to strengthen any organization. Strong leadership and communication skills with a mind for business backed by over four years of management experience. I'm pursuing a development opportunity where I can make a positive contribution towards success and growth.

EDUCATION

Web Development

Coding Dojo, Silicon Valley Python, PHP and MEAN

March 2016

B.S., Business Management

San Jose State University, CA

May 2013

EMPLOYMENT

Lead Web Developer/Manager 04/2017 - 06/2018

Morrocco Method Int'l - shop. Morroccomethod.com, www.morroccomethod.com/blog, Grover Beach, CA www.qigongmastery.com, www.thehairshaman.com

Technologies: PHP, WordPress, JavaScript, Jquery, HTML, CSS, PhotoShop, Illustrator, NetSuite, Bronto, SurveyMonkey, WooCommerce, Google Analytics

- In charge of the redesigning of four websites, front-end/back-end development, website security, reducing page load times, improving overall user experience and any other administrative duties of website.
- Lead a team of eight to creating beautiful product ads, web pages, e-mail blasts and set up sales campaigns.
- Improved SEO, mobile responsiveness, UI/UX design, front-end and back-end development, debugging for four separate websites, adding products to shop, content management and A/B testing.
- *Notable Achievements: Completely redesigned four separate websites, increased web traffic significantly, created new product categories, improved load time of all pages and improved SEO rankings.

Front-end Software Engineer

06/2016-11/2016

Laplace Systems - www.Solar-Link.net

Campbell, CA

Technologies: Java, Spring, Apache, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, Jquery, HTML, SASS, AWS, Xcode, Google Analytics

- Data mining, debugging, progress reporting, monitoring solar site activities, demoing prototype hardware, code reviewing and customer support.
- Back and front-end development with an emphasis on creating new front-end UI features and customer support.
- Enhanced the overall success of the business and software interface through updates to the front and back end
- *Notable Achievements: Made software entirely mobile responsive and cross-browser compatible, updated entire database to include all models of solar panels, improved load time of software and revised SEO of application.

Lead Front-end Developer

05/2016-05/2016

Good Karma Bikes - www.GoodKarmaBikes.org

Lead Sale Associate - Orchard Supply Hardware

San Jose, CA

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Angular.js, MySQL, JavaScript, Jquery, HTML, CSS, Google Analytics

- Lead a team of twelve to develop the UI/UX of the front-end and admin front-end of the website.
- Duties included: implementing SEO, analytics, front-end development, debugging and creating mobile features.
- *Notable Achievements: Helped create a back-end portal, so the owners could edit and update their website freely with any coding knowledge.

OTHER EMPLOYMENT

Branch Manager - River City Building Supply Inc. San Jose, CA 08/2013 – 10/2015

San Jose, CA 02/2013 – 08/2016

San Jose, CA 06/2009 – 10/2012

Restaurante Manager - Michi

Concession - Century Theaters San Jose, CA 04/2007 - 06/2008

TECHNOLOGIES & TOOLS

- JavaScript Bootstrap WordPress jQuery HTML CSS SASS/LESS NPM/Grunt NetSuite PHP Node.js Xcode
- PhotoShop Google Analytics Bronto AWS MySQL MongoDB GitHub Illustrator AngularJS AWS React Java